Guide to the Jean-François Bory Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Jean-François Bory Papers
1957-2015
GEN MSS 1460
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20
36 boxes + 2 cold storage, 1 record album storage
Writings, audiovisual works, photographic works, correspondence with literary colleagues, and other papers by or relating to French poet Jean-Franç̧ois Bory (1938- ). The materials document Bory's literary and artistic works across several genres and media, in particular his interest for visual poetry, sound poetry, film directing, and photomontage. Drafts, paste-ups, and proofs from literary projects, as well as production materials for the films SAGA (1967-1968) and Quant au livre (2004), provide evidence of Bory's creative process. Correspondence, article clippings, photographs of Bory, event programs, and promotional material for exhibitions trace his public career. Works of other avant-garde poets contemporary to Bory are represented in the collection by commercially-released CDs and DVDs of the multimedia label Son@rt, co-founded by Bory and fellow French poet Jacques Donguy.
Bory, Jean-François, 1938-
Donguy, Jacques ( Son@rt)
Conditions Governing Access
28 (record album storage) and boxes 29-33 (audiovisual): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
34-35 (cold storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 36-39 (computer media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from the Librairie Patrick Fréchet on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2016.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Writings, circa 1960-2014. II. Audiovisual Works, 1957-2013. III. Photographic Works, 1974-2015. IV. Correspondence, 1972-2014. V. Professional Papers, 1965-2013.
Biographical / Historical
Jean-François Bory (1938- ) is a French poet, writer, visual artist, and filmmaker whose avant-garde oeuvre centers on visual poetry and sound poetry.
Born in Paris, Bory spent part of his childhood in South East Asia before returning to the French capital where he based his career. In addition to numerous collections of poems, Bory's literary works include novels, monographs, essays, and articles of literary criticism.
The year 1966 marked Bory's first exhibits of visual poetry in London, Milan, and Venice. Two years later he participated in the pioneering sound poetry festival Text und Aktionsabend II in Bern. In 1983, Bory joined experimental poets Eugenio Miccini, Sarenco, Julien Blaine, Paul de Vree, and Alain Arias-Misson in forming the transnational group Logomotives. As part of his editing work, Bory co-founded the Éditions Agentzia (1968-1972) with Jochen Gerz and Arthur Hubschmid, directed the literary and sociological art magazine L'Humidité (1970-1975), and has served on the editorial board of CCP - Cahier critique de poésie since 1999. In 1998, Bory and avant-garde poet Jacques Donguy co-founded the production company and multimedia magazine Son@rt.
Scope and Contents
Writings, audiovisual works, photographic works, correspondence with literary colleagues, and other papers by or relating to French poet Jean-François Bory (1938- ). The materials document Bory's literary and artistic works across several genres and media, in particular his interest for visual poetry, sound poetry, film directing, and photomontage. Drafts, paste-ups, and proofs from literary projects, as well as production materials for the films SAGA (1967-1968) and Quant au livre (2004), provide evidence of Bory's creative process. Correspondence, article clippings, photographs of Bory, event programs, and promotional material for exhibitions trace his public career. Works of other avant-garde poets contemporary to Bory are represented in the collection by commercially-released CDs and DVDs of the multimedia label Son@rt, co-founded by Bory and fellow French poet Jacques Donguy.
Separated Materials
Approximately 200 printed items received with the collection (including unannotated publications by Bory, exhibit catalogs, reference works, and substantial runs of published periodicals) were removed for separate cataloging on 01/30/2018 and can be accessed by searching the library's online catalog.
Concrete poetry, French -- 20th Century; Experimental poetry, French -- 20th Century; Experimental poetry, French -- 21st century; Poets, French -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, French -- 21st century -- Archives; Sound poetry -- France -- 20th Century; Visual poetry, French -- 20th Century; Visual poetry, French -- 21st century; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Collages (visual works); Photographs; Photomontages; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Poets -- France -- 20th Century; Blaine, Julien, 1942-; Bory, Jean-François, 1938-; Dachy, Marc, 1952-; Donguy, Jacques, 1943-; Duwa, Jérôme, 1971-; Heidsieck, Bernard, 1928-2014; Métail, Michèle; Mréjen, Pierre; Royet-Journoud, Claude; Sarenco, 1945-
- Writings, circa 1960-2014; Series I; 7; 19 boxes + 5 oversize folders
  Arrangement
  Organized into four subseries: Books, Poems, Short Prose, and Edited and Translated Works.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Writings documents Bory's diverse literary production and creative process. The series comprises holograph drafts, typescripts, collages, paste-ups, proofs, cover designs, published texts in periodicals, and fragments for a comprehensive body of Bory's poetry collections, novels, monographs, individual poems, unpublished projects, and articles of art and literary criticism. Also included is one magazine maquette representing Bory's editing work for L'Humidité. From early drafts to published version, the types of material available for each writing project vary and are noted in file descriptions.
  - Books, 1966-2012
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    The Books subseries documents Bory's published and unpublished book-length projects, including poetry collections, novels, artist's books, and essays.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Box 36 (computer media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Abracadada
      - Prepress proof, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Copy with holograph corrections, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Copy annotated for public reading, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Appendice au cagibi de M. Gutenberg -- proofs with holograph corrections, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arte & cravatte -- paste-up, printed version, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Un auteur sous influence
      Initial title: Journal en ruine par un personnage déjà ancien
      - Drafts, typescripts, undated (Box 1, Folder 6-10)
      - Excerpt "L'auteur", in L'ennemi -- published issue, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Les baies de l'Île d'Yeu
      - Background photographs, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Typescripts with holograph corrections, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Proofs and printed version with corrections, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
      - "Nouvelle style Île d'Yeu" -- computer media, 1999; 1 (Box 36, Folder 278)
        Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - "Île d'Yeu 2eme copie" -- computer media, 2000; 1 (Box 36, Folder 279)
    - "Le bas-flanc de Saturne", publication project -- photocopies, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bêche -- paste-up, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bientôt le livre
      - Typescript with holograph corrections, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Soon English translation draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Paste-up with French and English versions, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Bienvenue Monsieur Gutenberg
      - Correspondence with editor Franck Pruja, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Proofs, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Le cagibi de MM. Fust & Gutenberg -- notes, proofs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Caillots & lignes déliées -- drafts, printout, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Cruellement défaut", book project -- drafts, photocopies, undated (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Le dernier dragon -- proof, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Les derniers jours de l'alphabet
      - Paste-ups, proofs, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
      - "Les derniers jours de l'alphabet" (1 of 2) -- computer media, undated; 1 (Box 36, Folder 280)
      - "Les derniers jours de l'alphabet" (2 of 2) -- computer media, undated; 1 (Box 36, Folder 281)
    - Dix-sept façons de rater un livre sur D'Annunzio
      - Typescript, proofs with [printer's] annotations, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
      - Excerpt "Ponge toujours partout", in Action Poétique no.153/154 -- published issue, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - 8 texts + 1 -- holograph and typed manuscripts, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - En effeuillant la marguerite -- proof, printed copy with holograph corrections, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
    - Un hiver près des ptyx
      - Drafts, cover designs, 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 36-38)
      - Paste-up with holograph corrections, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Japon, le retour -- list of editor's corrections, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Jean-François Bory (Paris-Zurich: Hubschmid, 1974) -- Ozalid test print, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
      Related Materials
      See also: Series III Photographic Works for other examples of photomontages by Bory.
    - Jean-François Bory: Objects - Romans - Essais [...] -- paste-up, proof, background materials, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 42-44)
    - Looping -- collages, [2011] (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Motfrage -- proof, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - La moustache de Lope de Vega dans les cheveux de Dorothy Parker -- cover design, printouts of two poems, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Onze nouveaux, nouveaux, calligrammes -- printouts, [2010] (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Pas tout le même jour -- drafts, notes, corrected proofs, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 49-54)
    - Plein signe, tome 1 -- Letraset maquette, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Pluies à Manaus
      - Background materials, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - Holograph and typed drafts, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - Discarded texts, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - Bound maquette, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Annotated proofs, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 60-62)
      - Proofs in A3 format, 2010 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 259-260)
      - "Pluies à Manaus HD J.F. Bory" -- computer media, undated; 1 (Box 36, Folder 282)
    - "Poèmes de bronze & proses de zinc"
      - Complete manuscript, related correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Excerpt "Poèmes de bronze & prose de zinc (suite)", in Doc(k)s no.46 -- published issue, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 64)
        Magazine issue also contains: "Les Avatars de Jean-François Bory," and "Le traducteur chez d'Annunzio".
    - Poemi senza parola -- proofs, 2009 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 261-262)
    - Poésies provisoires
      - Typescript, circa 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - Volume III -- prepress proof, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Post-Scriptum -- photographic prints and typesetted pages, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Pound III provisoirement posthume -- background materials, assorted drafts, photocopies, [2001] (Box 9, Folder 68-74)
    - Prolégomènes à une monographie de Raoul Hausmann -- paste-up, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - Retour au Japon, calligrammes et fragments de journal intime -- printed copy with holograph corrections, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Roussel, S.A.R.L. -- drafts, paste-up, list of editor's corrections, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 77-79)
    - Sombre dîner en ville -- drafts, proofs, and printed copy with holograph corrections, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 80-82)
    - Untitled publication project -- printouts, photocopies, undated (Box 11, Folder 83-84)
    - Cover designs for unfinished books, 1979; undated (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Poems, circa 1960-2014
    The Poems subseries documents the creation and publication of individual poems composed by Bory through drafts, collages, proofs, and magazine issues. While Bory integrated most of these poems in the poetry collections found in the Books subseries, he also published them individually in literary magazines and reworked them over the years. The subseries also evidences the evolution of Bory's methodologies for creating visual poems, from mixed-material collages to printouts of digitally-created typographies and forms.
    - "L'argent", in Approches -- proof with annotations, [1966] (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - "Blue" -- printouts, undated (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - "Un carré de soie tissé artisanalement dans le quartier d'Utano à Kyoto", in Offerta Speciale no.24 -- published issue, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - "Chirico" -- drafts, undated (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - "Clapotis de l'espace mental", and "Grandeur nature" in Fig no.6 -- published issue with annotations, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 90)
    - "Com'era dolce quella vita" -- mixed-material collage, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - "Complément" -- printouts, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 91)
    - "Conduite forcée" -- typescript, circa 1965-1975 (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - "Couleurs" in Ailleurs, no.6 -- magazine issue proof, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - ["Dans un petit poème..."] in OEI no.5 -- published issue, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 94)
    - "Duchamp dernier délai, segment 1" -- proofs, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 95)
    - "Duchamp dernier délai, segment 9", in Java no.25/26 -- proofs, printouts, published issue, 2003-2004 (Box 12, Folder 96-97)
    - "Ecce Scriptor" -- drafts, printouts, excerpt in Fin no.10, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 98-101)
    - "Errata"
      - Holograph and typed drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 102)
      - In Minuit no.20 with "Hommage à Pavlov" -- published issue, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 103)
    - "Erreur" -- word in gouache, undated (Box 13, Folder 104)
    - ["Et moi subitement, là… "], in Ouste! no.7 -- published issue, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 105)
    - "Fir un txt Pr" -- print, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 146)
    - ["Le goût frénétique ABC..."] -- holograph, printouts, undated (Box 13, Folder 106)
    - "Grumeaux dans la phrase du temps" -- printouts with holograph corrections, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 107)
    - "Là!" -- typescript, circa 1965-1970 (Box 13, Folder 108)
    - "Landscape" -- printouts, undated (Box 13, Folder 109)
    - "The Last Day of Mr. Lax 1, A Tribute", in Fin no.9 -- drafts, published issue, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 110-112)
    - "Un lundi au bord de la mer", in Dichtungsring no.28/29 -- published issue, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 113)
    - "Malherbe revisited" -- typescript, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 114)
    - "Le métronome d'Erik Satie (extraits)", in Action Poétique no.188 -- published issue, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 115)
    - ["Miroir..."] -- collage on four sheets, [2014] (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - "Naître, c'est sortir d'Égypte" -- color printouts, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - "Opera omnia", and "C...comme" -- typescripts, undated (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - [Plissé, gris, plissé...] -- typescript, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - "Poème équation" -- typescript, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - "La poésie est...", 1993
      - Proofs, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 121)
      - In L'avioneta no.9, accompanied by reproductions of sculptures by Bory -- published issue, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 122)
      - In De simples nuits de roses no.1 -- pamphlet, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - "Poesiola con Cummings / Little Poem with Cummings", in Cervo Volante no.5 -- published issue, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - "Poetry is gone", in Full -- drafts, published issue, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - "La porte de la mer à Miyajima" and other visual poems -- prints, undated (Box 15, Folder 147)
    - "Promenade au bord du ruisseau", in If no.14 -- published issue, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - "Quelques cours en direct de la bourse" -- holograph drafts, undated (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - "Rang-Zéro" -- typescript, circa 1965-1970 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - "Rome, café gréco", "Hotel Regina, Chambre 64", C=EM2?", and "Boîte noire" -- holograph drafts and printouts, undated (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - "Seul", and "La Peste", in Stereo Headphones vol. 1, no.2/3 -- published issue, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - "Science" anagram -- gouache on cardboard, undated (Box 15, Folder 148)
    - "6 pages de périple", in Action Poétique no.159 -- published issue, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - "Spot" in Delo no.2 -- published issue, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - ["Ein Stein / Eine Hyperbole..."] -- typescript, circa 1965-1970 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - ["Thecris..."] -- drafts, undated (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - "3 Haiku concrets", in Fin no.20 -- published issue, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 135)
    - ["Vas-tu enfin m'expliquer..."] -- drafts, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - "Zip", in ZIP Zone d'intérêt poétique no.22 -- published issue, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - Selection of poems and texts for public reading, Bordeaux -- annotated photocopies, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 138-140)
    - Selection of poems and texts for public reading, École nationale des Beaux-Arts de Lyon -- annotated photocopies, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 141)
    - Series of four visual poems -- screen prints on golden paper, undated (Box 15, Folder 149-152)
    - Ten poems in L'Énergumène no.6-7 -- numbered copy printed on velin d'Arches paper, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 142)
      Contains: "La poésie est...", "Cauchemar", "Bouquet pour Marion", "Poème pour l'ecclesiaste", "Angoisse 3.", "Voyage dans le temps", "Poème paresseux", "Poème lèpreux", "Poème copié", and untitled.
    - Untitled poems in "Fascicule 9: Jean-François Bory", Comme une revue -- circulation copies, 2001-2002 (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - Various holograph drafts and typescripts, circa 1960-1970 (Box 14, Folder 144)
      Typescripts of several poems from an original folder bearing the autograph note: "Manuscrits et tapuscripts années 60/70 [...] Tapuscrits et divers pour ma participation au livre de Pierre Garnier La poésie spatialiste Gallimard 1968"."
  - Short Prose, 1965-2014
    The Short Prose subseries includes published magazine issues and catalogs featuring short stories, articles, essays, and prefaces written by Bory, largely reflections on the contemporary artistic and literary worlds.
    - "Bain de sang" in Le Cahier du Refuge: Hommage à Ghérasim Luca -- published issue, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - "Un confetti autobiographique", in Simultaneità no.2/3 -- published issue, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 155)
    - "Copeaux d'un journal indien", in Fin no.22 -- annotated copy, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 156)
    - "Coup de vieux dans l'éternité", in Arnaud Labelle-Rojoux: Remakes, Galerie Lara Vincy -- published copy, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 157)
    - "Le déchet du festin", in arTitudes international no. 24/26 -- published issue, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 158)
    - "Dépôt de bilan", in Nos Années 80 by Bory, Bernard Comment, and Gérard-Georges Lemaire -- copy with holograph corrections, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 159)
    - "La dernière interview", in La Revue littéraire no.2 -- published issue, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 160)
    - "L'espion de Dieu (à propos des tendances futures de la création littéraire)", in CNAC magazine -- published issue, 1987 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 263)
    - "Fragments d'entretien", in Exit no. 2 -- published issue, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 161)
    - ["Des hommes de lettres ne rien attendre..."] -- holograph and typed drafts, undated (Box 16, Folder 162)
    - "Où peut donc", in Fondcommun -- published issue, 2014 (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - "Out of order", in Rabascall: Paysages, Musée Puig C.D.A.C.C. -- published catalog, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 163)
    - "La poésie visuelle dans le monde", in PERI no.21 and in Opus International no.40/41 -- published issues, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 164)
    - "Réponses", in Ailleurs no.8 -- published issue, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - "Scientose" and "L'écran anticipé", in Ailleurs, no.7 -- proofs with corrections, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - "Sophie Melon: sculpture, pastels, et encres", Galerie Sabine Puget -- brochure, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - "Tapage nocturne", preface for La mille et troisième nuit by Gérard-George Lemaire -- copy with holograph corrections, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 168)
    - "Tentative pour un théâtre spatial" -- typescript, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 169)
      Note: " Pour Pierre Garnier, Anthologie du Spatialisme, Gallimard"
    - "Tottenham Court Road (From London with Lola)", in L'ennemi -- annotated issue, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 170)
    - "Trente-cinq Question-Réponse à propos de William S. Burroughs", in If no.11 -- published issue, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 171)
    - "Triste cena in città", in Secondo Tempo, Libro settimo -- published issue, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 172)
    - "Tv. Deum" -- holograph, undated (Box 17, Folder 173)
    - "Un vernissage", in L'ennemi -- typescripts, corrected proof, published issue, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 174-175)
    - Untitled short story -- holograph, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 176)
    - Untitled drafts, undated (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Edited and Translated Works, 1973-1978
    The Edited and Translated Works subseries offers limited documentation of these facets of Bory's literary oeuvre, containing a partial translation by Bory of Brazilian concrete poet Augusto de Campos' "Galaxias", and material relating to Bory's 1970s experimental poetry magazine L'Humidité.
    - "Galaxies", original by Haroldo de Campos -- typescript, undated (Box 18, Folder 178)
      Translated from the Brazilian Portuguese original by Bory and De Campos.
    - L'Humidité, no.26, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 179)
      Paste-up of unpublished issue no.26 dated December 1978, accompanied by cover proofs for other issues of the magazine.
    - L'Humidité essay layout, undated (Box 18, Folder 180)
    - Notes on L'Humidité letterhead paper, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 181)
- Audiovisual Works, 1957-2013; Series II; 6; 10 boxes + 1 film reel
  Organized into four subseries: Son@rt Productions, SAGA Film Archives, Quant au livre Film Archives, and Recordings.
  Series II. Audiovisual Works contains audiovisual material, computer media, and analog files documenting Bory's sound poetry performances and film directing activities, the multimedia magazine Son@rt, as well as other experimental poets' works.
  - Son@rt Productions, 1998-2013
    Sorted by material type under the headings Files and Media, and then arranged chronologically in publication order with corresponding Son@rt issue numbers.
    The Son@rt Productions subseries include CDs and DVDs produced by Bory and Donguy's label Son@rt. Son@rt CDs and DVDs feature poetry readings, performances, reviews, and interviews by international artists.
    - Files
      - Cover design and booklet for 2 Films: La peste, La vie nouvelles (1967) (son@rt 042), 2005 (Box 19, Folder 182)
      - Celebrity café #01: Chroniques, poésie, histoire des avant-gardes, musique, danse, arts plastiques, intermedia (son@rt 054) -- published issue, 2013 (Box 19, Folder 183)
    - Media
      Boxes 30-31 (audiovisual): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      Box 39 (computer media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Donguy, Jacques and Matta, Ramuntcho. Tag-Surfusion (son@rt 001), 1998; 1 (Box 30)
      - Bain de sang suivi par 3 poèmes de Ghérasim Luca (son@rt 002), 1998; 1 (Box 30)
      - Un auteur sous influence précédé de divers poèmes (son@rt 003), 1999; 1 (Box 30)
      - Text und Aktionsabend II (son@rt 004), 1999; 1 (Box 30)
      - Giorno, John. Life is a Killer (son@rt 005), 1999; 1 (Box 30)